VREZH BABAKEKHIAN

MIDDLE+ FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

◆ BARCELONA, SPAIN

◆ +34 687 644 904, +7 914 706 06 06(WA)

• DETAILS •

Barcelona Spain +34 687 644 904, +7 914 706 06 06(-WA)

workraiden@gmail.com

Date of birth 12.07.2001

Nationality
Half Armenian and Russian

Driving license

В

• LINKS •

Personal Website

Github profile

LinkedIn

Telegram

• SKILLS •

NestJS

Next.js

React

Typescript

Git

Docker

Relational DBs

ElasticSearch

Redis

PHP

Python

C++

MongoDB

Linux

Unix OS

LANGUAGES

Russian

English

Armenian

PROFILE

Passionate Web Developer with expertise across all development stages. Skilled in UI, testing, debugging, and technologies like Docker, Git, TypeScript, NestJS, and React. Effective in both solo and team projects, committed to delivering standout web solutions.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Full stack developer at CROSSNETICS, Remote

March 2023 — Present

- Developed a comprehensive marketing web platform utilizing advanced AI algorithms and web3 technologies.
- Implemented automated project documentation and typization via tools like swagger for both backend and frontend that significantly boosted development process.
- Developed a RESTful API that handled over 1 million requests per day with response times under 200 millisecond.
- Utilized a diverse tech stack including NestJS, Next.js, TypeScript, MySQL, Redis and ElasticSearch.
- Implemented a microservices architecture that improved system modularity and reduced dependencies between components.
- Optimized database queries to improve application performance and reduce response times by 10-25%.

CRM full stack developer at FaceStellar, Remote

December 2022 — July 2023

One of the lead developers of *Customer Relationship Management* system for <u>FaceStellar</u> beauty saloon.

- Developed complex CRM system from the ground up leveraging Node.js + Express and React that improved customer service efficiency by 30%.
- Created a Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) pipeline that allowed easy deployment process

PhP back end developer at Highway logistic group, Moscow

January 2022 — August 2022

- Oversaw the maintenance and optimization of MySQL databases, ensuring data integrity and performance enhancements, contributing to a more robust and reliable data management system.
- Developed and integrated new sections within the company's **relational database** architecture, leading to enhanced data organization and accessibility.
- Played a key role in the expansion and enhancement of the company's CRM system by implementing advanced features, complex classes, and controllers, resulting in a more dynamic and user-friendly platform.
- Led the debugging efforts for critical software components, identifying and resolving numerous issues, which increased system reliability by 15% and reduced downtime
- Managed a migration of the company's software stack from PHP version 5 to 7.4, ensuring compatibility and leveraging new features for a 40% improvement in system performance.
- Worked closely with front-end developers to **architect** and **build** new **system sections** from scratch, enhancing the user experience and interface functionality.

HOBBIES

Snowboarding, surfing, motocross, gaming, skateboarding, music, bass guitar Responded to high-priority development needs, efficiently delivering urgent front-end and back-end features that improved overall system responsiveness and user satisfaction by 50%.

System administrator assistant at OOO "Kinoprokat" , "Moscow" cinema, Vladivostok May 2020 — September 2020

Assisted System administrator with maintaining Cinema's Database.

EDUCATION

Bachelor, London School of economics & Higher School of Economics, Moscow/London

September 2019 — July 2023

Double degree Data Scientist Bachelor program.

London School of Economics and Political Science:

Combines data science, machine learning, statistics and mathematics. The programme uses a rigorous approach, has a mathematical focus and involves applying data science to the social sciences.

Higher School of Economics:

The aim of this programme is to train analysts and data scientists who are experienced in modern methods of machine learning, software development, working with big data and developing analytical models for business. The programme is based on the successful experience of HSE University's Bachelor's programme in Applied Mathematics and Informatics and the longstanding work of the London School of Economics and Political Science (University of London).

School 13 with deep learning English course, Vladivostok

September 2008 — June 2019

★ COURSES

Game Programming and algorithms with C++, ID Coding & Engineering Academy(Imperial College London)

July 2018 — August 2018

Demonstrated Proficiency:

- · Animating sprites
- Creating console-based games
- Identifying and fixing bugs
- · Making custom art assets
- · Using object oriented programming
- · Creating adaptable game objects
- Re-creating classic games
- Implementing simple AI
- Understanding program structure

Oxford summer English for 13-15 years, Oxford Royale Academy

August 2016

CEF Level: B2

Has achived EF EPIs score:

84%(equivalent to C! on CEFRL scale)